Anatoliy Yastreb

Software Engineer

Shinagawa-ku, Tokyo, Japan +81 080 8111 6803

anatoliy.yastreb@gmail.com https://ayastreb.me

I'm a web software engineer with vast experience in eCommerce and web development. I've led teams of 3 to 4 developers and have experience setting up team workflow according to industry's best practices.

I'm passionate about complete process of product development - from requirements collection to deployment and impact analysis. I enjoy working with smart people, crafting software which brings value to customers, and continuously improving my skills.

In my free time I contribute to open source projects and learn new technologies.

Skills

Languages

JavaScript, Ruby, PHP

Frameworks

React, AngularJS, Laravel, Sinatra

WebServices

SOAP, REST, JSON API, oAuth

Databases & Search

MySQL, CouchDB, Redis, ElasticSearch

Testing

Jest, Jasmine, PHPUnit, Selenium

Continuous Integration

Bamboo, Capistrano, TravisCI

Experience

Senior Software Developer at Luxury Fashion Trade GmbH (fashionette.de)

Düsseldorf, Germany, 2013 – 2017

Technologies: Magento, PHP, Laravel, Solr, Varnish, Microservices

Led development team of 3-4 in various projects, including new features implementation, payment methods integration and online shop localization in 16 new countries for Germany's biggest online designer handbags retailer.

Senior Software Engineer at Magento, X.commerce, Inc. (an eBay company)

Dnipro, Ukraine, 2011 – 2013

Technologies: PHP, SOAP WSI, REST, Redis, MongoDB, Gearman

Worked on Magento Core API, performed R&D on Magento 2 API platform. Participated in Magento Connect and Magento GO (SaaS) projects development.

Web Developer as Independent Contractor

Dnipro, Ukraine, 2007 – 2010

Technologies: AWS, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Implemented various web projects for international customers.

Junior PHP Developer at eTek Systems

Dnipro, Ukraine, 2006 – 2007

Technologies: PHP, XML, Atom

Worked on international customer's web projects and in-house tools.

Projects

Money Tracker

Maintainer, 2017 - Present

Offline-capable progressive web app for personal finance management.

Implemented with React, Redux and PouchDB/CouchDB.

Does not have a backend — communicates directly with CouchDB server.

Bandwidth Hero

Maintainer, 2016 - Present

Chrome extension which compresses images on the page via proxy server to save data. Proxy server is implemented with Node.js.

Jekyll Maps

Maintainer, 2016 - Present

A plugin that allows users to easily create different Google Maps on a Jekyll site.

Jekyll

Team Captain, 2016 - Present

As @jekyll/build team captain I help triaging incoming issues, review pull requests and occasionally contribute to bug fixes, refactoring and feature development.

Meal Planner

Founder & Primary Developer, 2015 - Present

Recipe recommendation and nutrition balancing service.

A health & fitness progressive web app built with AngularJS, Sinatra & ElasticSearch.

Education

Coursera

Data Structures and Algorithms, 2016

Udacity

Tech Entrepreneur Nanodegree, 2015 - 2016

National Mining University, Dnepropetrovsk, Ukraine

Bachelor, Management, Economics, 2004 – 2008